Okay, so let's talk about the cost
management plan then.
Now, just like any of the management
plans, the cost management plan is one of
the subsidiary management plans that make
up the project management plan.
So again, remember just to the review,
the project management plan is made up of
the subsidiary plans, the baselines,
and some additional components.
One of those subsidiary plans is a cost
management plan.
right any of the management plan at least
most of the management plans right are one
of the subsidiary management plans and
remember with any of these management
plans right we're documenting how we're
going to perform this process of this
knowledge area right this is a key word
right the keyword is the word how and how
is the keyword there how are we going to
plan execute monitoring control this
particular knowledge
area in this case this
knowledge area is cost, cost management.
So, how are we going to estimate our
costs?
What formulas are we going to use?
How are the cost going to be estimated?
What methodology, what convention are we
going to be using, and so on and so forth.
That's going to be documented here in the
cost management plan.
Before you can estimate your cost, you
need to know how to estimate your costs.
Before you can come up
with a budget, you need to
know how we're going to
come up with the budget.
So all of those procedures are going to be
documented here in the
cost management plan.
Now, there are many, many different ways
of valuing your project.
Different industries are going to be
valuing projects very differently.
So, for example, a construction project is
valued very differently to, say,
an IT project, which is valued very
differently to, say, a research and
development project and so on and so
forth, right?
It's going to be, you're going to be
valuing your product, you're going to be
valuing your project very
differently based on if you
have a tangible product
versus an intangible product.
So there's many, many different
conventions out there.
Now, the convention that you need to know
for the exam, the methodology that you
need to know, is something called earned
value management.
And that's going to be covered in a separate
video, in fact, a few separate videos.
We're going to be covering the formulas
and the concept of EVM earned value
management, also known as Eva,
earned value analysis.
So that's a methodology that you need to
know, the convention
that you need to know.
But again, whatever convention is going to
be used, it's going to be documented here
in the cost management plan, regardless of
which industry you're in.
How we're going to estimated is going to
be documented here.
What software tools are we going to be
using?
I mean, in reality, the project manager,
you're just going to be using software
tools, are going to be just plugging
numbers in, right?
It could be even an Excel spreadsheet.
You're just going to be
plugging numbers in and, you
know, the calculations or
the formulas are already there.
But again, what systems are going to be
using?
What tools are we going to be using?
Where is it going to be documented?
Where is it going to be recorded?
Again, all documented here in the cost
management plan.
Also, things like precision and accuracy.
So our accuracy is going to be plus minus
10%, for example.
We're going to talk about
the various different accuracy
levels, but just as a very
simple example, right?
Our accuracy has to be, you know,
up to plus and minus 10% of the final
cost, right, or even precision,
right?
So when we are coming up with a cost
estimate, how we estimate into the nearest
penny or the nearest dollar, or the
nearest thousands of dollars.
So what's our cost estimate?
If you've got a billion
dollar project, you're not
going to be estimating
down to the nearest penny.
Even a million dollar
project, you're not going to be
estimating down to the
nearest thousands of dollars.
You're going to be estimating down to the
Sometimes there might be the nearest
$10,000 of dollars.
So again, what level of
accuracy, what level of
precision are we going
to estimate our costs?
It's going to be documented here in the
cost management plan.
Also, the confidence levels, right?
So, in a previous video, we covered the
pert formula, right, where we had the
confidence levels, a 68% confidence, a 95%
confidence, and so and so forth, right?
1 sigma, 2, sigma, 3 sigma.
Well, that's all relevant here as well in
cost management, right?
So, again, what confidence levels do we
want to estimate our costs at?
That's all going to be documented here.
Also things like the
work breakdown structure,
remember the WBS, a work
breakdown structure, right?
One level above the work package is known
as a control account, but the control
account can be set at any level of the
WBS.
So what level of the work breakdown
structure are we setting our control account?
Again, that's going to be documented here.
And what's our rules?
What's our procedure for estimating our
cost and then aggregating and going up
each layer of the work breakdown structure
to come up with the overall cost.
Again, what's our procedure for that?
That's all going to be, again, documented
here in the cost management plan.
So any kind of procedures.
What's our threshold for going over
budget?
Do we have a threshold?
So again, that goes back to the accuracy.
What kind of accuracy levels are we going
to be estimating that?
And what happens if we are going over
budget?
First of all, we have to define what does
going over budget mean?
So for example, if it's $100,000 project,
your $20,000 over budget, that's a big,
you know, that's a big increase.
That's significant.
But let's say it's a $100 million project
and we're 20,000 over budget.
Well, that's not really significant at
that point.
So what's our threshold for going over
budget?
And then what happens if we are, right, if
we see that we're
going over budget, right?
What do we do in that situation?
How do we handle that situation?
How do we handle that procedure?
So that's, again, all going to be
documented here.
Plus also procedures
such as fluctuations in
currency, how do we handle that situation?
Fluctuations in cost of raw materials.
If suddenly it's volatile, the price of
raw materials are suddenly very volatile.
How do we handle that situation?
Again, all of these
procedures are going to be
documented here in the
cost management plan.
Also reporting as well, how often are we?
we're going to be estimating our cost,
right?
How often are we going to be a running
reports on our cost estimate?
Is it a daily report?
Is it a weekly report, monthly report?
Right.
So again, that needs to
be planned and discussed
at the beginning of the
beginning of the project.
And then, of course,
it can change, right, all,
everything we've been
talking about, right.
They can change over time.
Remember, progressive elaboration,
but you're going to be making updates.
You're going to make updates to the cost
management plan.
You know, as the procedures change.
So again, as with any management plan, the
cost management plan is
documenting procedures.
In this case, documenting
procedures regarding the
cost and regarding the
budget for the overall project.